better you can hey yeah
welcome everyone in the wasabi research
club number 17 and I'm very happy today
because today finally we are going to go
through the go through our research the
cryptographic primitives of our research
and if you have not paid attention to
the last two episodes then pay attention
today because this is going to be the
final scheme that we have came up with
and this is what's going to be in
Bitcoin in a couple of years time maybe
two weeks just a quick overview on on
what we are doing right here is that in
Vasavi we would like to replace the
mixing protocol in order to make the
mixing well a couple of things to fix
about the mixing for example we could
remove the minimum denomination we could
reduce or maybe completely make the
change disappear in the mixes we could
have more blockchain space efficient
mixing and we could also make
transactions in the mix and how that
this this these ambitious plans here
requires us to be able to break coins
down or merge them together in any way
shape or form and when I'm talking about
coins here I'm talking about off chain
Co enjoying coins which is star which is
being which are living between the input
and output registrations of the coin
during phases so that's the big picture
here
we have roadmap and I would like to give
divert to ishtvan or you while who would
like to start Thank You function take it
yeah but before we going deeper like a
small correction that this is not our
scheme so we are standing on the own
giant shoulders so we just give slight
modifications towards the existing
schemes so yeah our added value is I
would say almost negligible like just
with an epsilon anyway so first we want
to provide some lightweight background
because we understand that there might
be some newcomers who joined the
research club or are not as familiar
with this key with this scene so maybe
we should start with commitment schemes
like just a really quick review right or
yeah shall we started commitment schemes
you well or or yeah I think that's the
most logical place all the commitments
are the most sexy things so yes so like
it's not that important that the that
the viewer knows any instantiation of
the commitment schemes it the you or
should just understand that we have two
algorithms this commit wait don't you
want to explain the commitment scheme
with my article that should be really
fun
yeah okay ah yeah with sex medium no
para yeah I mean this is a special type
of commitment scheme but yeah so but but
before going into this like let's just
give an overview that so we have a
function which is called commit and it
allows one to commit to a message be
with the randomness our and this
algorithm outputs a so-called commitment
which is denoted as C and then later it
allows the commuter to open this
commitment and anyone so this is called
opening a commitment and they can check
whether this opening of the commitment
is correct so what this achieves this
commitment scheme is that one can think
of it as someone puts a pan in a box as
Adam says in his example and then later
one wants someone put in this pan into a
box then they cannot change their mind
so this is called binding property but
we also want that if someone just has a
look have a look at the box then they
should not be able to tell what's inside
the box what's inside the commitment
what message was committed and this
property is called hiding and pretty
much that's in let's I think suffice is
to have for you why do you want to add
something for commitment schemes and
yeah so maybe we can move forward to max
if there is no any comment to commitment
schemes
I guess maybe just so opening a to
finish the analogy opening the
commitment is like opening the box you
after you promised you show everybody
what you put inside the box in the first
place and the most familiar example of
commitment schemes are hashes with a
random string added because there's a
difference from just hashes to
commitments if you commit to the same
message twice normally you don't want to
reveal that you committed to the same
message twice so that's why you add
randomness and it's not just the message
yep
so that commitment schemes are like
cornerstones of crypto but I suppose
like 99% of the audience already heard
about them so let's move forward to
where Linda on max okay lindell's
this is like our Bible if you are into
crypto then most likely you already are
familiar with this book by you telling
that and Yonatan cuts okay so what is an
H Mac an h-back provides basically data
integrity on messages so if you know
what is a digital signature you can
think of an H Mac as the symmetric key
counterpart of digital signatures so one
can produce with the K key an H Mac on a
message and then later this so-called
learn Mac stands for message
authentication code this tag can be
verified with the very same so note that
for issuing this Mac and verifying the
magazine he needs to be taken so this is
like a symmetric key counterpart of
digital signature so this doesn't not
provide public verifiability but still
it ensures that the message sent along
with the Mac ensures that the message
was not modified on the on the wire
right and H Mac is like I think one of
the most important and famous
instantiation of Mac's
but in the wabi-sabi we rely on a
different Mac right anything I should
add two Macs
so if there's nothing I should add to
max then maybe we can move forward to
the signal paper so but what did you say
just just a question Mac is the
symmetric part of what was that yeah
okay so like just think of like this
would be if this would be a digital
signature scheme then here okay you have
a general key generation algorithm you
generate the public key secret key and
then for example here instead of a Mac
you would have a sign algorithm which
and which usually takes this the secret
key as an argument and then it produces
similarly not a tag but we call it a
signature and then later the
verification algorithm in case of our
digital signature scheme takes as input
as the public key of the issuer of the
signature so there's an asymmetry so in
a digital signature only does a secret
key holder can produce digital
signatures but the public can verify the
validity of the digital signature given
the message and the signature and here
only those people can verify the
validity of the Mac who has access this
risky so this is kinda this is a
relaxation of a digital signature or
yeah so this does not provide public
liability and each Mac is the most
popular Mac yeah but in wabi-sabi we we
will use and apply an SPO called
algebraic Mac and this was I think the
most important observation what you've
all made that we don't need don't really
need blind signatures or digital
signatures at all because in a mixing if
you apply
coordinator then you don't really care
about public verifiability because only
the coordinator should be able to verify
these credentials yeah so this makes
this was the most important observation
I think so far that we don't need this
asymmetry the coordinator issues
credentials and then only the
coordinator needs to verify it in output
registration but now I'm I'm getting to
forward it is do I didn't realize that
but then I ignored the literature on max
for this because I thought it was mostly
relying on bilinear groups so it's Jonas
Nick again for like the third time we
have to thank him for reminding me to to
work correcting my misunderstanding and
reminding me that I should take a closer
look at that can I ask another thing
that if the Cayenne does not need to
verify then I mean in in show me and
Cohen join at least the client needs to
verify that the signature is correct but
what the was the thing here also here do
it later I think it's it's part of the
that's addressed as part of the protocol
but I think we should save that detail
for after we we go over the definitions
that we're gonna use because we need
those definitions too but the short
answer that still in this case the
coordinator can convince the client that
it gave out a correct Mac or on the
message so this is that's the answer
thank you and not only that that all the
users have a mark issued by the same key
so the coordinator cannot produce
different like tags for sorry that's an
overuse overloading of terminology so
that
the coordinator cannot use a different
key for each user in order to do naanum
eyes them later it has to to prove that
it's making use of the same announced
key so right anyway thank you the only
thing you forgot to say is to spoiler I
laughed but that's fine okay so let's
move to the signal paper right or do we
want to maybe cover not this Sigma Nu
which one should I shall we think I
think first we should go through the
preliminaries of the Sigma paper and
then if people want to go over zero
knowledge proof sand the notation then
the first two pages of damn birds
introduction to Sigma protocols yeah
it's a really nice example so we can
depending on how it was we can either
skip that or or not yeah anyway if you
are dear viewer if you're new to this
space and like these two introductory
texts are your best friends
so Sigma protocols and commitment
schemes and zero knowledge protocols but
going back to the signal paper so here
pick six I think yeah okay this is not
that important I suppose yeah let's go
over because there were some confusions
about like some of the feedback that we
got so we might as well define this
terminology because we use it later it
should be its base okay so we are
working on a finite cyclic group you can
think of your favorite elliptic curve so
this J denotes the point the set of the
points of this elliptic curve usually in
crypto we use the prime order prime
order elliptic groups yeah and and we
have this additional three
functionalities which allow us to map
arbitrary this means arbitrary bit
strings to to group elements so we
should just
have this as a given that such functions
exists and then similarly we can map we
don't need those yeah okay so should I
just keep it yeah I think so okay so we
have this and then I think this is the
important stuff
so now let's introduce what is amor more
precisely what is the algebraic back so
again we have this beloved elliptic
curve group and then we have a key
generation algorithm which outputs two
scalars in the ins EQ so do the
coordinators private key consists of two
elements from zq x0 and x1 then the
coordinator the can generate max on a
message m with the secret key by
choosing a random point on the curve and
then outputting well here they denote it
as Sigma so it's like already you can
think of it as some kind of signature so
this Mac this algebraic Mac consists of
two points you and due to the x0 plus x1
times M so the authors of this signal
paper used multiplicative notations and
then again the coordinator can verify
the validity of of a Mac given the
coordinator secret key and the message
by just basically recomputing it so how
can he recompute the mac so again just
applying the same formula he will get u
double prime and then he just needs to
check with the u double prime equals new
to the x0 plus x1 times m if this
equality holds then the mac is correct
and the message was not modified
otherwise outputs
well invalid so and then we have
desirable desirable security properties
right so but I think those yeah let's do
the minor note on the notation so here
they write U and u prime but later in
the paper they call it U and V so
uppercase u and uppercase v are this
paper owners is a little bit math so we
will we need to write a long-long errata
letter them so we will do don't worry ok
so now we know what is the commitment
scheme what are max algebraic max what
we need to know maybe we're here just
few words about ZK or or shall we
explain ZK here Sigma I think the
definition that section 2.4 I think is
is it's it's the same notation that we
use and it's pretty concise for yeah
right thread and this is um do you want
to explain it to you well I don't know
you're doing a good job where do you
wanna are you tired already so 0
approves these are magical create
creatures animals but they are not that
not that worrisome so but it doesn't say
the algorithms it has anyway yeah but
what do you mean the algorithms like
prove verify pigeon I was expecting
something different something similar
whatever I think maybe the original CMZ
13 paper has such definitions but sorry
I didn't I didn't prepare that we have
something here so okay let's stick to do
anyway so knowledge proof system has
basically many algorithms but let's
simplify it has two algorithms of proof
and the verify
so approver wants to prove that a
relation holds for X and W so W is
called the witness and it's in it the
prover wants to keep secret and witness
so it doesn't want to publish publicize
the witness otherwise it will be trivial
to prove this relation so how can we
circumvent this issue so the prover
generates a small proof by and then the
verifier can give an axe and PI but not
given that the witness can verify that
this relation holds so this is basically
the footprint of a 0h2 system and here's
define relation maybe because that's
yeah unintuitive yeah duh like in the
first higher level you can think of any
relation just involving a predicate
which used is x and y and some public
values but for example the most simple
and like the grandfather of all zero
knowledge proof systems is the Schnoor
identification protocol which allows to
prove approver that given Y and the G it
knows such acts that G to the x equals y
so this is called knowledge of discrete
log protocol and or we can have another
type of neurological system which is
called the oak the knowledge of opening
of the Patterson commitment so here we
prove that without releasing without
making any information whatsoever about
the exponents that we know x and y is
such that Z equals e to the X multiplied
by H dy
right and then we can combine such
proofs with logical and logical or write
and but in our case the most important
is that approver can prove that they
know an opening of a commitment
or in our generalized commitment so if
we have not just J and H as generators
comprising this element Z but we have
multiple generators then approver can
prove the knowledge of all these
exponents up here without releasing any
information about them right so this is
kind of a very crude very initial
introduction to the knowledge process
now maybe we can go to lobby lobby if
there is no any comment and if if this
is unclear we can consider doing like
the first page or first two pages of
Sigma I guess it's up to you guys to
decide no it's a it's a document for for
cryptography probably for implementing
this we need something different because
I think the document is okay s as it is
if I keep the refer can understand it
yeah I think from an implementation no
point of view it's really enough if you
just think of these like it just gives
you two functionalities you can prove
something and then you can verify some
this the validity of this proofs
so I think maybe this is this this might
be the closest and the most helpful
thing we can offer I don't know if it
helps I think yes actually I disagree
here I think if we do go through so like
let's let's quickly go through this noir
identification protocol as an
interactive protocol and then I think
everybody will recognize like Schnoor
signatures because this is how these
things are made concrete and I think
important thing is just to remember that
none of the proofs that we require need
anything more than Sigma protocols it's
just that it could be more efficient and
we also want to use the feature myristic
to make this non interactive are you or
you in favor yeah I mean if there's need
we can go over to start identification
typically okay so here just one minor
note is in his example he discusses this
of like just the integers mod piece and
large prime yeah but but for our
purposes like since the finite field Z
sub Q is also happens to be a group
because every field is a group we can
think of that as the elliptic curve in
this case yeah exactly
okay so shall we go over then yes please
okay so we again we have a verifier has
access to P as the characteristic of the
group doesn't really matter G and H and
the prover wants to convince the
verifier that he knows such witness
exponent which which is right if we
raise it to G then we have we will have
H so the statement we want to prove is
that G to the W equals H in this group
without leaking any information about
the weakness okay so so again this is
the statement we want to prove and then
this is like zero knowledge 101 so if
you will ever take another class in zero
knowledge proof system then this will be
most likely the first or one of the
first protocols you will see so it's a
three move protocol
first the prover chooses a random R in
the group and sent a to G to the R to
the verifier okay so P is the proverb is
the verifier then we and our correction
in this case even though the the scalar
field and the group are the same thing R
is a scalar so in the elliptic curve
case P chooses our from the the field of
like the the prime the the finite field
whose order is the same as the order of
the group yeah yes yeah I mean it's
really stuff a little bit but okay
nicely so we choose is a challenge e
from from this isn't really matter this
group and sends it to P and then the P
the prover sends Z equals air plus e
times W so basically the prover masks
the witness with this challenge e what Q
so basically this is kind of why the
verifier will not learn anything about
the witness and then the verifier can
check this equality here and correctness
so from any 0h protocol we require three
properties correctness so if the prover
knows such a witness which satisfies the
relation then the prover should be
always and should be always able to
convince the verifier so like it's super
simple to see that this relation holds
if the prover has the correct witness
then we also require soundness from a
proof system so if the prover doesn't
know such a witness namely the proverb
wants to lie or tries to lie then the
prover should not be able to lie or with
some or only with some negligible
probability and then we also require
zero knowledge which is a little bit
more technical to formally define but
zero knowledge means that the verifier
does not learn anything about
the witness which is the information the
approver would like to keep secret so
yeah this is a three move so called
Sigma protocol the way they are the
reason why they are called Sigma
protocols because maybe is there
anything like that no I don't think so
no it's a [__] meme it should be
called the Z protocol or something it's
like three hundreds like if you draw
lines or how to say if you draw the
direction of the communication then it
looks like a sigma but but your body's
right so let's see yeah okay so I think
is everybody comfortable with that I
guess yes because we are pretty familiar
with that so if you understand so
basically all the zero knowledge proves
what we need in wabi-sabi are really
similar to this this specific Sigma
protocol like they are siblings or
brothers and sisters to this protocol so
if you understand nor identification
platycodon basically you almost
understand all other Sigma protocols so
that's good news and now we can maybe
move forward to a piece of it right
okay or her is there any question
comment critic there is none
okay so first let's just start with I'm
just a high-level description of the
protocol shall we also define
input/output Prudential attribute would
it make sense I don't think so
okay so the user acting as a list to
submit your input value so like anytime
we think of inputs or outputs we just
represent them as integers at namely
their Satoshi
well you so we extract away any other
information such as scripts strict
bupkes etc and whenever the user submits
an implicit EXO it also sends K pairs of
attributes so each input has K
attributes a value attribute and a
serial number attribute and you should
think of these attributes its commitment
to these messages so just by seeing MV I
and MSI you will not know anything about
the underlying B eyes and EFTS eyes and
so hand because the coordinator doesn't
know anything about these values whether
they are well formed or not the Elliots
also sends some very large proofs to
convince the coordinator that certain
relations hold for these m VI and msi
most importantly we want to prove that
the some of the underlying VI eyes add
up to this public V in and that and and
we also want to convince the coordinator
then that we did not print any more
money namely the
this MV eyes lie in certain range so you
should not be able to adjust the
register 21 million bitcoins more
importantly if you come in with like one
Satoshi and you register - a billion
Satoshi and plus a billion in one
Satoshi the sum is still equal to VN
that's why they have to be positive
that's how here so I want to expand on
this and say like not only are those
attributes commitments we want them to
be
Patterson commitments because we want
them to be homomorphic and homomorphic
means that the sum of two commitments is
the same thing as a commitment on the
sum of the two messages and this is also
why we use an algebraic Mac because the
algebraic Mac kind of preserves these
nice properties and if we didn't do this
if we didn't use Patterson commitments
and algebraic marks those that zero
knowledge proof of the storm would be
much much more complicated it could not
be a simple Sigma protocol or actually
we don't even need this Sigma protocol
that the way that we defined it but well
I'm getting ahead of myself
these groups are verified and they are
valid then the coordinator issues k-max
message authentication codes on the
requested attribute and also the
coordinator needs to convince now the
client the alias that these Macs are
well formed so that the coordinator does
not want to cheat a list okay so now we
just give a high-level overview so we
don't really describe how these
attributes and the credentials look like
so let's move forward or yeah is there
any questions to input registers
I mean now we are really just having
just a glimpse of the protocol we will
go into the details later
so just exactly what gets transferred
there so the DMV n ms the value and the
serial number Vektor the commitment
Chara arrays anyway so those get
transferred the range proofs regarding
the range proofs is it bulletproof or
just normal range proofs I mean as of
now you can think of favorite and most
below the range to but most likely I
suppose we will implement the most
efficient form which is currently the
state of the art is blue across here
alright and anything else that gets
transferred some and a small growth we
call it like a soundproof which
convinces the coordinator that the sum
of the committed v eyes adapt to be in
anything else you know that's it you you
summarized it correctly ok thank you
that's pretty simple so like you can
think of you have one Bitcoin and you
register you want to have 10 10.1 new TX
o outputs Bitcoin outputs then you
request 10 credentials for this and
group attributes actually I think he was
said that some kind of relationships has
to be also proven on M V and M s is that
are very you referring to the range
proofs and some proofs or no the Sun so
you want to prove anything with regards
to the serial number you don't really
care because the the Alice cannot cheat
there so it's Alice's yeah me so
yeah and it's gonna cheat anyway so we
don't really care about the serial
number commitment but we only care about
the value commitment and we each
individual mvi we will require a range
proof and we require this some proof I
don't think there's any ZK we require 4
m VI and MSI is there anything like that
you well I don't think so I think in the
version 0.1 we still wrote that there
should be a proof of knowledge of the
opening of the serial number commitment
but yes that it's it's not contributing
anything I mean if the user doesn't know
the opening of the serial number
commitment and that's her fault so but
yeah we could require something like
that but I don't think I mean the worst
that could happen is that Alice
sabotages the protocol by registering an
input that she can never open but that's
the same thing as refusing to sign in
the end or refusing to register an
output so it's it's the same like
unsolvable denial of service of Alice
disappears all right thank you
so ok what is an output registration now
with in yet another network identifier
acting as Bob Alice comes along to
register her I would put the user and
okay so now comes the fun part
previously we added commitment now Alice
randomizes the commitment um maybe the
viewer doesn't know what it means but
it's ok we will explain it later and by
randomizing this these attributes now
this makes these attributes unthinkable
to the previously
attributes by the coordinator and that's
the rationale behind randomizing these
attributes but still Alice can convince
that even though these attributes are
randomized still Alice can convince or
Bob if you wish can come with the
coordinator that these are valid
credentials issued by the coordinator
and that's that's why we also use this
algebraic Mac or are the signal paper
most more precisely and yeah anyway
verify a small thing because there's a
slight mistake here we need to fix
so it says a valid credential but it's
any number of credentials so the whole
point of this is you register each input
independently and you get several
credentials for each input and then you
go and you pick and choose whatever
combination you want for every output
registration so every user can in
register several inputs and can register
several outputs and no input should be
linkable to any other input or output
and no output should be linkable to any
other input or output yep and we again
in the output registration phase we will
require some zero knowledge proves what
properties should Alice convince the
coordinator about so let's start with
the serial numbers Alice will just or
Bob will just reveal these serial
numbers and that's where we will have
double spending protection a can I ask
yep
the serial number stuff as far as I can
see
wouldn't a simple blank signature scheme
could work with the serial numbers
or or not I think the effect is the same
or what would be the gain
no I'm just asking that is that
something swappable I don't think there
is a gain because right yeah we are
using the serial numbers for as as we
are using it for the exact same yeah I
think they are interchangeable that's if
I understand the question correctly I
think it's it's not possible because I
mean we need the algebraic max stuff or
something like the ACL scheme which is
line signature scheme with attributes if
we only do a blind signature on the
serial number here then nothing
constrains the user to only use the same
serial number with the same amount so by
doing it with a single Mac that covers
both of these together the Mac is only
valid if you expose the corresponding
serial number to the the same amount
okay thank you this is this is exactly
what I was I was looking for that okay
so the serial numbers and the values are
actually connected together but but the
MV in and M s and M VI and MSI's blindly
sign then this attack vector is fixed
right yeah and and that's exactly what
the ACL paper let us do right so there
we have a blind signature scheme with
attributes and the attributes are
exactly the same as as here would
they're just Patterson commitments the
difference is the randomization is more
complicated to prove things about the
signatures are larger so here as a Mac
is a single field element and two group
elements whereas
the ACL scheme I think it's like 1/8
tupple of like I don't remember how many
of those are group elements and how many
are I think they're all group elements
not that it matters because they're the
same size there's 32 bytes roughly so in
the ACL scheme I think is much harder to
understand than the algebraic max so
like this is meant to be a plug-and-play
sort of sorry a plug-in replacement for
the ACL scheme and in this sense it is
like the the blind signature scheme with
attributes gives us exactly the same
thing it just also provides a public
verifiability of these signatures which
we don't actually need so again and we
need to prove some relation between
these attributes because the user wants
to register an output to be the specific
Bitcoin value and maybe this bitcoin
value is constructed using several other
credentials so again here we will need
some proof these are all spelled out in
the paper so don't worry the crypto
details will come soon and then yeah
that's it
the user submit all this trust and then
we the coordinator verifies this proves
and how to register a shin is done
basically signing face is pretty much
the same we use the same as the in
current wasabi so the user just checks
whether her desire the output is
included among the output of the coins
and transaction if this is the case it
signs the transaction and sends over tor
the signature if this is not the case
then the user awards the protocol right
let's go to the crypto D test if there
is no question it is there any yes I'm
good okay so there's a lot of parameters
of the coordinators so anytime you see
the with some subscript it's just a
generator point it's just an element a
point in an elliptic curve and more most
importantly no one knows the underlying
discrete logs pairwise discrete logs
no one should should be able to to know
this and then the we want to talk about
the individual subscripts like at least
categorically I think so W and W prime
are part of the secret key there using
the keyed verification credential scheme
x0 and x1 are the generators used for
the algebraic mac so they correspond to
x0 and x1 which are the part of the
secret key in the algebraic mac Givi ng
s those are our notation in the original
paper these are denoted gy 0 gy 1 to n
they're used for the in the Mac for
verifying the attributes or sorry for
assigning the attributes or tagging the
attributes I guess is the correct term
then we add G sub G & G sub H for
Pettersen commitments and finally
there's G sub V which is used in the
verification of the algebraic mark yeah
and this is Christy of the coordinator
and
yeah maybe maybe we could change later
from issuer to the coordinator but in
the document as of now we use issuer and
coordinator a little bit interchangeably
and so these are the public parameters
of the coordinator these are the secret
parameters and now let's move forward to
the input registration so can I have a
question from Lucas actually so these
public constants of this look looking
how would this look like in c-sharp code
can you hear me yeah yeah well in
c-sharp called in it's just I don't
remember the new and Bitcoin library but
it is just a point right is just to
create a point in fact aye-aye sir paper
no no paper a pull request on and
decline where the recent way to derivate
one point one generator from another
generator but in a way that you don't
know they they shout to go from one to
another
I don't know how to play this and there
are hash function that's usually the yes
it uses is this is like a HUD function
of the of the previous one to generate
the the next one or something I don't
remember exactly the details but in in
in an Bitcoin for example you have a sec
SEC P 256
k 1 dot G big G that big G it's a liquid
pure point I think that the class is
called Big E C point if you have that G
big G that is the the generator so it's
basically and we can use okay for what
it's worth I think the traditional
method to do this is called hash and
pray where you start by hashing a
message in this case it just be the
variable name and you use that as the
x-coordinate and you check is this X
coordinated like on the curve does it
like map to corresponding Y that's on
the curve and I think with like a
probability 1/2 it should be the case
for SSCP 256 K 1 I suppose it should be
like almost because the order is very
close
sorry my bad yeah like if you have 200
bid then like pretty close to 1 yeah for
some reason I thought the the order was
2 to the 128th for a sec my bad yeah
because the rows I forget whose Rho
algorithm is like square root of n right
it's know for a security parameter of
128 you need 56 a group order of 2 to
the 56 more or less no run is that
that's not relevant anyway so if it's
not on the curve and you just say oh
sorry just a comment in the chat then
you can see how in c-sharp it could be I
mean it's just an elective cure and and
that's it I see that's very useful
actually Thanks I was just not sure how
how low we can go do we have these
building books already or or not is it
guaranteed that the discrete log is not
known between these we can't I mean we
can find a way to derivate one from the
other one off we can just select I don't
know I couldn't feel comfortable
selecting the values by by the way that
the signal paper defines it is that hash
to point function I think it's called
and you just hash the variable name take
that as the final score oh yeah okay yes
that that's a good way yeah it's not a
valid curve point then you just append
like an integer we increment an integer
right like do the variable name the
variable name dot 1 or something try to
hash that if it's still not working
hash point 2 and soon enough you find a
point that's the hash yeah yeah I I feel
I feel okay with that I mean if it
doesn't exist the point try it with the
next one yes it's a good way my bad so
this this is just the characteristic of
the scalar field and this is the actual
size of the elliptic curve group so it's
very close though yeah it's close so
like to divide this with two to the 256
it's three still it will be pretty close
to one so the hash and pray method
should output you almost instantly this
almost instantly a valid point on the
curve yes i-i've never I never seen a
point that is a number that is that that
give me an invalid point all the points
I tried it's always funny
nice okay so let's go but here
Oh part of that the subtlety of the hash
though is we need to convince the users
that the the coordinator did not
generate these points maliciously so
it's not just choosing a point it's you
need to choose a point that everybody
knows is safe maybe we can hash the
first I don't know ten words of the
white paper and then we will have some
points in the third so it should be
trying because you discuss the function
earlier it's called hash to G and it's
just the definition right okay so the
input registration because it split it
simple do we want to discuss the
parameter store what they mean
it eats it up you and I or a rich one
yeah it's a little bit unintuitive but
like what they do is they allow this is
used as part of the credential perfect
okay never mind let's let's do that
later after we do the show protocol so
just remind me to go back to the
parameters so we want we have input UT
XOR with value V in and we want to break
it into K inputs with value VI so to
that end we submit K Patterson
commitments so M VI is the Patterson
commitment to VI
namely a J - J sub G to the our VI
so this is the blinding factor and this
is J sub G to the V I so this is a
comment that there's no commitment to VI
blinded with RBI okay so we have K
commitments to be a similarly we have K
commitments to the serial numbers so k /
there's no commit
the serial numbers and for each value
commitment we also include a range proof
which says that I'm I have a commitment
which is basically a point on the curve
it's a commitment to be high with some
randomness rvi these are the witnesses
so I'm not going to tell you the
witnesses but I will be I will be
convincing you that still the underlying
value lies in the range so it's less
than say 21 million bitcoins so it's not
some negative value so we don't you
don't know you don't need to know how
such zero logical system looks like we
just need to accept that such a animal
exists and then okay so we were able to
prove that the commitments are well
formed now we need to convince the
coordinator that the sum of the sum of
the VIS add up to the claimed registered
in patootie rec so how come just a
comment and the you I don't know if you
said that the are B I am si the blinding
factors are chosen randomly oh yeah
that's right that's right I forgot to
tell ya you are absolutely right yeah if
they are not chosen randomly then Alice
is screwed and and the coordinator could
do unionize Alice if the values are not
padded here okay so this some proof this
is super simple we apply the same trick
we already
described several times in previous
muscle research club videos so it's
super easy how to have week improved the
stump of committed values in the petals
and commitment equals the public value
so we just need to the coordinator can
just calculate the product of the value
commitment and the product of the value
commitments will be gg to the sum sorry
Gigi to the sum of the yet to the sum of
the randomness values our VI the
blending factors and gh to the V in so
basically this is the this if this
equality holds then L is indeed convince
the coordinator that the sum of the
committed messages adapt to the in yeah
also not this is not zero knowledge
proof it's not a Sigma protocol either
but it could be for our purpose like if
you since when you reveal a sum of
random numbers you don't reveal anything
about the original numbers and those are
just blinding terms this is still what's
called witness hiding but it's strictly
speaking it's not zero knowledge and the
like we could do it zero knowledge by
making a Sigma protocol that proves
knowledge of the sum and like eventually
shows so we would do like G to the to
the PI sum and then prove that this
commitment lose the other commitment
opens to a commitment to VN or something
like that
we don't see a reason why that that
needs to to be a sigma protocol so just
to clarify that the this pi term is is
literally just the sum of the exponents
yeah okay so we have the some proof
which is pretty simple pretty standard
we discussed it several times what is
missing from the input registration is
that now the coordinator accepting and
verifying these proofs the coordinator
should give out these valid max and so
for each for each so this is the message
the coordinator is signing if you wish
this is not an insignia but a Mac and
the coordinator will convince Alice that
the Mac is Val formed so like without
this Z knowledge proof it would be
really bad because maybe Alice just got
to get some garbage from the coordinator
and we don't want that so this is just a
form of description how come how perform
a description of a zero knowledge proof
system that achieves convincing Alice
that V is a is a valid Mac with respect
to these public keys public parameters
of the coordinator yeah because
obviously the coordinator doesn't want
to tell Alice the underlying secret
parameters in the first place so yeah
maybe I have a lot of clear in
explaining this so you could help me
so first the T and you are also part of
the Mac I would say yeah yeah that's
true and then this is this is exactly
how the coordinator proves to Alice that
it's not using a different key for each
user so that it can be anonymous them
later the the reason is because CW and I
are published in advance
everybody should check that they get the
same ones if they fetch at different
times over different tor circuits so
these parameters
we well-known just like the round
denomination keys for the blind signing
or in the current protocol and then this
proof convinces Alice as a proof of
knowledge that this was relative to the
the key so Alice cannot use this to
prove to anybody else that her Mac was
derived correctly or sorry in this case
she can because this is probably gonna
be a non-interactive proof so anybody
could verify it but if she does that she
reveals her Mac so sorry that was a
little confusing but the point is Alice
only learns from this proof that this is
a Mac generated by the the secret keys
committed to by the parameters yeah okay
so with that we conclude the input
registration phase and now we can move
forward to the output registration which
is a little bit more complicated but not
that much so now let's say Alice got all
together T valid credentials so T valid
Max and now Alice just want to use in
the first output registration just ass
out of this D right
yeah so this this is in the first place
what we do and this this is called the
show protocol which is more in more
detailed explained in the signal paper
but it is even harder to understand the
single paper because in the signal paper
there are many typos and errors so we
maybe this is the right place to learn
it and it's also more general we only
need a specialized version of it because
we only use one kind of attribute that's
really true so what what's happening
under the hood is that we have this nvi
and msi commitment
these are reran demised namely really
randomizing me means that it's
multiplied with another point on the
curve just to look just to make it look
even more random and then we have this
randomized commitment and 0h magic
allows at least to prove that he has a
valid Mac on the rear end of my stuff or
more precisely that she just show she
just shows the rear end of my stuff but
still can say that look I know well is
Mac behind these three randomized things
maybe I was again a bit clearer but this
is this is what happened yeah what is
the the V the big V is the last run the
recession's weight in so that's that
should be VI
I think that's fickle of the eyes okay
and it's the last component of the Mac
yes perfect thank you
this is a type of from our part yeah I
fixed it I think you're using a an old
version of the PDF I don't know maybe I
fixed that okay sorry I think I fixed it
in the like the markdown
work in progress branch I should I
should bring that over to the overleaf
version another question in T because
the the the Mac has a component at each
component but this T is the number of of
Mac's or the combination a random scalar
it's a component of the Mac and it's
just a random field element no but but
Lucas makes a point here that we also do
not see the number of credentials and
it's gone yes oh sorry yeah but a TI is
the one that comes from the Mac and I
don't think we ever used he again after
this paragraph yeah we should choose a
different because here's there's the
class yeah yeah my bad you have an eye
like an ego I try to understand yeah but
this is the valid point because this is
called like C times K or something
instead of T okay this is confusing
indeed yeah so a little bit so little
letters in the alphabet we should have a
longer alphabet right or I don't know
maybe we should use Hebrew letters at
you have degree the Greek alphabet the
the English alphabet the Arabic alphabet
[Music]
why I think when one important thing for
the notation is anywhere you see a
subscript I that means it's part of like
it's related to specific credential
except where I made that typo with V I'm
sorry that's a helpful intuition though
it's just so that you could to write
perfect document there will be always
errors and typos well one step at a time
right okay so is there anything to add
to this credential validity so this is
where I wanted to bring up the issue air
parameters they're not just used in
order to convince Alice that she got a
valid Mac they're also used in here to
generate the proof
so both CW and I are used
sorry no only I in this case and this
value Z Z is generated by Alice it's
kind of generated one way so Alice
generates it by taking I and raising it
to the power Z but the coordinator
calculates I in a different way it
calculates it from the randomized
commitments and from its secret key yeah
but if you want you can also just as of
now think of this whole show protocol or
credential loyalty as a black box so
Alice randomizes the commitment and
proves that he has a Mac she has a Mac
which is valid but not not showing the
Mac itself to the coordinator maybe
maybe hopefully now we explained it well
I then
can you repeat that Lucas
looks like the internet is gone in
Argentina no okay so you can ask it as a
youtube comment okay so like how can we
prevent users overspending and then we
have one one less now just this right
what do we prove here
okay but this is trivial so what this is
also trivial whatever
so overspending prevention so the user
has the user has this as credentials and
we want to prove that they add up to
this output you txo well you be out so
again at this point in time Alice has
randomized commitments and this is CBI
CBI denotes the randomize commitment a
CBI is just basically mvi with
randomized with GV and by a user chosen
randomizing factor VII but if we spell
it out then this point is essentially
has three generator points and then each
generator point we have the exponents
are essentially sums terms of either zi
r VI or VI and we want to say something
about the sums of V eyes so this is
pretty simple if the coordinator takes
the product of these randomized
commitments then this is what we will
have okay so what we can do is we can
just open the commitment on GV and GG
how can we open the commitment with
respect to these two generators well we
just tell the coordinator the exponents
corresponding to these generators so
essential
the proof which is the Gannet in zero
knowledge proof but rather a witness
hiding but this is just small stability
just a technicality so the proof is two
scalar field elements the sum of the Z
is in the sum of the RBI's
so hence if we give these two group
scalar field elements the coordinator
the coordinator can just raise GV to the
first proof element and GG to the second
proof element and this is the well you
what Bob's claims to be the Sun so the
right hand side can trivially be
calculated either from the proof or is
public knowledge and their left hand
side is just the sum of the rear end of
my commitments so if this equality holds
then also the claim the statement what
Bob is trying to prove holds right so
this is this is it and so this is how we
can prove prevent overspending okay and
then in the very end of the output
registration phase we also want to
prevent double spending and double
spending is pretty similar that the
spending prevention is pretty similar to
the previous knowledge group we have as
we randomized serial number commitments
so again MSI is a commitment to the
serial number what which is now real
randomized by the user so the real
randomized commitment looks like GS to
the Z IgG to the RSI and gh to the si so
now the user needs to conduct the
coordinates a mistake in the this is
because we move the sections so this is
redundant with the CSI defined at 2.2.1
it's exactly the same one what's the
point what's your point
this one says she randomizes the serial
numbers again
but that's she already randomized them
to prove the credentials valid so same
CSI I just took it as a reminder okay I
know it's an editorial mistake because
women of things are okay so basically
the user wants to convince the
coordinator that given CSI the user
knows
gir Si and si such that so this is
called knowledge of representation so
the user knows that the representation
of this point with respect to these
three generator points without telling
the underlying individual exponents so
we have such a zero knowledge proof
system you don't need to know how it
works we have it out of the Shelf of the
Shelf and but in our case what we also
need to do need to do is that we can
publicize si because that's how we will
that so we need to public publicize si
and the serial number because otherwise
we will not accept on the output
registration yeah it's it's pretty easy
like you give the serial number and you
give Patterson commitment to not exactly
but like G to the Z G sorry G as to the
Z
Jiji to the RSI I proved knowledge of Zi
and RSI with respect to that commitment
and the coordinator can can confirm that
this commitment x GH to the SI is the
same as the randomized commitment
exactly thank so but if that that
concludes the output registration phase
and then we have wabi-sabi at least in
draft 0.2 in chinese GG means penis
something every day
so maybe hopefully we will have some
Chinese viewers and they can correct me
voice sitting here alright thank you
guys maybe do you do you have anything
you would like to talk about before we
go all right I think this as a no this
was a pretty intense session I will
definitely watch it a few times and
hopefully I understand more I have maybe
one last thing so we can post it in the
description but I would really recommend
to anybody who wants to read into this a
little bit more the original algebraic
mac paper i think is a
a very nice read wait let me give you a
precise title I'm sorry it goes wrong
paper yes
so algebraic maxed and key verification
anonymous anonymous credentials this is
where the stuff was introduced so
melissa chase Sarah Michael John and
Greg's Arusha whose name I keep
forgetting I'm so sorry Greg the signal
paper takes this there's two algebraic
Mac algorithms described in there one
relying on the generic group model for
security proof and the other relying on
decisional diffie-hellman so the signal
paper uses the first one and extends it
to support attributes where the
attribute values are not just scalars
but arbitrary group elements I think
it's very well written it's also got at
the very end like after the security
proofs there's a concrete instantiation
of the zero knowledge proof for this
slightly simpler scheme so that's a
really good reading I think and also
personally I'm kind of new to this zero
knowledge stuff so I found Ivan damn
guards introductory materials really
helpful both this one and the one on
commitment schemes and zero knowledge
protocols actually this one was probably
more helpful because it really goes
through the like the logic and the
definitions it it's a very clear
description of the difference between a
proof a proof of knowledge zero
knowledge proof zero knowledge proof of
knowledge etc etc and also covers stuff
like cryptographic simulators which are
needed for for all of this stuff both as
a theoretical concept
and for the a be blind signature scheme
you actually need to write a simulator
so it's really helpful to understand how
the Abed blind signature scheme in the
ACL paper we discussed like why that
even works anyway so those would be my
reading recommendations thank you
sorry I have a question you said that
given we are creating this dis max from
the commitment for the Palio commitment
and the serial number commitment you
said that this is the magnitude that we
need to use because this preserves the
on morphic the what sorry either I love
the word but then the property of Murphy
I'm a morphism
of the commitments and where are we
using that again so well why did we have
to preserve that just just making this
edit proves easier like we just want to
make our lives easier so if we have this
nice properties then for example this
overspending prevention like proving
sums becomes like almost trivial yeah so
we we use it implicitly in these some
proofs and also an input registration
phase yeah you can imagine something
that uses an H Mac but then doing the
zero knowledge proof should become
really complicated you need something
like ZK snarks or ZK Starks or something
like that like art enjoy arithmetic
circuits and the proving time is going
to be really long and the proofs are
gonna be yeah it's it's just probably
requires a trusted setup so that's like
the the main advantage is it makes the
all the zero knowledge proof
extremely simple on the same sort of
complexity as just the Schnoor signature
even the range proofs I would argue or
are still as simple it's just the same
idea like repeated multiple times and in
bullet proof they make it much more
efficient by doing it like that there's
a cool recursive trick but conceptually
it's still very much like a Sigma
protocol and not like one of the more
general purpose user knowledge proof
systems it seems to me I I'm not sure
but it seems to me that the harder
computation is performed by the client
or I mean from the from Alice right no
from or but not from the coordinator but
anyway thank you you have any any idea
of how how hard these computations are
on the server side in the on the
coordinator side and how many an elected
curve multiplications let's say well I
cannot really give precise numbers but
all of these proofs are like super
lightweight so I I think it's just a
question of milliseconds so I'm not
afraid at all I think the most expensive
part is the arrange proofs because in
the range proofs you need to do a binary
decomposition so there's like a vector
commitment to the individual bits and
like you need to compute the inner
product and I think that's so that that
would be like I think 51 if we use 51 as
the range times I guess it's like four
multiplications and then like you can
make it into a giant multi
exponentiation
it's basically oh of n
in the the parameter of 51 and there's a
protocol
so somebody linked on a slack channel if
you go it's fun very quickly to
lightweight dot money so this is the
Nanaki I think it's pronounced it's like
a Greek word this is a very similar idea
but it uses the older algebraic max
scheme and it uses alga Moll encryption
and blind issuance so I would say it's
ever so slightly more complex because of
the blind issuance then the newer signal
scheme and he has concrete performance
figures that I think should give us at
least an order of magnitude estimate
that's item 9 so in your opinion the the
the range proof I mean it requires the
the inner product of the each of the 51
beats for what the other element the way
the range proofs work is you make a
commitment to like I actually I don't
know how the commitments in bulletproof
vests work exactly I need to review that
but as far as they like the the
statement being proven you do you take a
vector that's like some generator does
the same generator for the commitment
value to the power 0 to the power 1 to
the power 2 no sorry you do 2 to the
power like 0 1 2 times that generator
and then you you so you have these
generators that are the same for
everybody and that's just like a vector
of the powers of two and then you
compute the inner product of another
vector which is 0 or 1 for every binary
digit in the amount so you do like 0 or
1 times the first generator for you know
the first digit 0 1 times the first
generator the second generator for the
second digit and so on and then and the
inner product if this should be equal to
the Patterson commitment of the amount
and then you also need to prove for
every one of your bit commitments you
need to prove that it's exactly 0 or 1
and the way that you do this is you take
the a commitment times I think the sorry
the commitment witness the value times 1
minus that and this would be 0 for like
if the bit is 0 then 0 times 1 is 0 and
if the bit is 1 then 1 times 0 is 0 but
for every other value it's gonna be
nonzero so like you take all of this
stuff together and like one giant
polynomial and like that gives you
eventually a commitment to 0 and that's
what like ensures the validity of all of
this and and the bulletproof stuff like
you can do this as a Sigma protocol but
the bulletproof stuff does something
like really clever where they they
basically do like the recursive
decomposition of this problem and like
they add if this was an interactive
protocol it would take log n
interactions but with the Fiat ramier
heuristic you can still make it non
interactive and so the the prover and
the verify still do oh and work like
they would in a Sigma protocol but the
actual resulting proof size is only
logarithmic it's it's very small
hopefully that that makes sense and just
as a caveat I'm like I barely understand
that stuff
like so so I probably made okay yeah I'm
just asking this because I see a lot of
operations and the server is one only
one that had to to do this for every
every user for every single a pair of
commitments and we we have now the C or
C++ performance with c-sharp in this
kind of stuff but I'm just I just was
curious thank you I think so if we
compare it to that lightweight money
scheme the danaka scheme the credential
that like we have is very similar to
what he calls a token not a wallet so a
token spend is very similar to a output
registration and a I think he calls it a
wallet top up or like that's very
similar to input registration but a
little more complicated because it
requires like another proof and he uses
bullet proof for everything and the the
performance figures that he gives this
is on a curve 255 1/9 and rust it's
still only a few milliseconds per per
operation so if we take that as like an
order of magnitude let's say you know
it's 10 times slower I still think it's
very reasonable for a fixed number of
participants like this should be like
not more expensive than say like the
number of signatures you need to
validate a block or something like that
in Bitcoin so I don't know I mean maybe
like I think I'm really overestimating
here
but let's say it's like 10 seconds of
compute overall in an entire round I
think that would would probably be
enough and this stuff is like one of the
reasons we prefer this over like
bilinear groups and zk snarks and all of
that it's not just more complicated
conceptually it's also that those
underlying primitives are not as
efficient like for bilinear groups you
need groups with like a cofactor they
can't be groups of prime order because
you need like cyclic subgroups inside of
them so that's a like a bigger curve
order and typically they're not as like
the implementations are not as fast
either so I think from all the schemes
we consider this should actually be one
of the more performant ones even though
it's it's still probably at like at
least a hundred times slower than just a
plain blind nor signature all right
thank you guys for today and like share
and subscribe and there's a goodbye
let's hear some word from our sponsor
[Music]